<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
  <title>Collector Of Jack - A Jack Daniel&apos;s Tennessee Whiskey Blog</title>
  <description>A blog about collecting Jack Daniel&apos;s bottles and memorabilia from Chris Hammond.</description>
  <link>https://collectorofjack.com/</link>
  <atom:link href="https://collectorofjack.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 17:02:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s Distillery Series Twice Barreled Tennessee Straight Rye Whiskey</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The 13th release in the Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series, formerly Tennessee Tasters has been announced, a Twice Barreled Rye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about this release is hard to find so far, but it is being reported that it will be available in April 2024, and as with all other bottles in the series, only available in Tennessee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we know so far, mostly based on the label found online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;: Twice Barreled Tennessee Straight Rye Whiskey&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: A unique rye grain bill twice barreled in new, charred American white oak barrels for added depth and character.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof&lt;/strong&gt;: 107&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size&lt;/strong&gt;: 375ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Selection&lt;/strong&gt; #: 013&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Released&lt;/strong&gt;: April 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Selected by Whiskey Taster, Jason Marski&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra time in a second, new charred oak barrel sets this Tennessee Rye Whiskey apart, with aromas of sweet smoke and burnt sugar on the nose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledStraightRyeDistillerySeries</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledStraightRyeDistillerySeries</guid>
    
    
    <category>Distiller Series</category>
    
    <category>Tasters Series</category>
    
    <category>375ml</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s Twice Barreled Heritage Barrel Rye</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Special Release from Jack Daniel’s brings us another heritage barrel selection, and another twice barreled offering (&lt;a href=&quot;/TwiceBarreledAmericanMalt&quot;&gt;like 2022&lt;/a&gt;) at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s edition is a Rye, first barreled in new oak barrels, then followed up with a second maturing session in some extra toasty heritage barrels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These 700ml bottles are bottled at 100 proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-jack-daniels-website&quot;&gt;From the Jack Daniel’s Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A SPECIAL TWIST ON OUR ORIGINAL HERITAGE BARREL EXPRESSION
The Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Special Release series highlights an annual limited innovation from the Jack Daniel Distillery and this year’s release is a twist on the original – Heritage Barrel. Twice Barreled Heritage Barrel Rye is a celebration of the whiskey-making traditions of our distillery and the barrel-making expertise of our cooperage. The 2023 Jack Daniel’s Special Release is a one-of-a-kind experience crafted from 70% rye, 18% corn, and 12% malted barley and twice barreled for a complex taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the heritage bottles lately, the labels are primarly screen printed on the bottle, with some paper label at the bottom on the front, and the rear (actually side) label is also paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;front-label&quot;&gt;Front Label&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s&lt;br /&gt;
Uniquely Crafted Handmade Barrels&lt;br /&gt;
Twice Barreled&lt;br /&gt;
Special Release&lt;br /&gt;
Tennessee Rye Whiskey&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;paper-label&quot;&gt;Paper Label&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Straight Rye Whiskey aged in new oak barrels and then matured in our handmade heritage barrels which are heavily toasted and lightly charred to create a unique flavor.
100 Proof | 50% ALC/Vol | 700ml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The back/side label is paper and reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sideback-label&quot;&gt;Side/Back Label&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Limited Bottle No. HBR-#####&lt;br /&gt;
This special release series highlights the Jack Daniel Distillery’s innovation. Our rye whiskey is matured in new American charred oak barrels and then in our uniquely crafted heavy-toast, low-char, heritage barrels. We extend this one-of-a-kind craftsmanship to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previous-heritage-barrels&quot;&gt;Previous Heritage Barrels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/HeritageBarrel&quot;&gt;2018 Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/HeritageBarrel2019&quot;&gt;2019 Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020SpecialRelease&quot;&gt;2020 Jack Daniel’s Barrel Proof Rye Special Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/JackDanielsSpecialReleaseCoyHillHighProof&quot;&gt;2021 Jack Daniel’s Special Release Coy Hill High Proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/TwiceBarreledAmericanMalt&quot;&gt;2022 Jack Daniel’s Twice Barreled American Single Malt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2023&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 100&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 700ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $70&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Bottling Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 7/11/2023&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1st Barrel Entry:&lt;/strong&gt; 3/13/2015&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2nd Barrel Entry:&lt;/strong&gt; 11/18/2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-is-jack-daniels-twice-barreled-heritage-barrel-rye-worth&quot;&gt;How Much Is Jack Daniel’s Twice Barreled Heritage Barrel Rye Worth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondary for this bottle seems to be quite a bit less than last year’s release, usually around 175.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-of-jacks-value-assessment&quot;&gt;Collector Of Jack’s Value Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t spend more then $200 for a bottle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledRye</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledRye</guid>
    
    
    <category>Heritage Barrel</category>
    
    <category>Heritage</category>
    
    <category>Twice Barreled</category>
    
    <category>Rye</category>
    
    <category>Special Release</category>
    
    <category>700ml</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s Single Barrel Barrel Proof Rye</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s ventured into Rye over 10 years ago and has regularly been adding to their line since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2023 Jack Daniel’s started bottling and releasing their Single Barrel Barrel Proof Rye, to go along with their Single Barrel Barrel Proof Tennessee Whiskey. This will be regular release going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the initial release it has been difficult to find on the shelves, but in the past couple of years, Single Barrel Barrel Proof Tennesse Whiskey has been hard to come by as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barrel is the typical Jack Daniel’s single barrel bottle, with the gold label that you should be familiar with. The print on the labels are in green, versus the usual black for the normal barrel proof. The neck contains a green label with the barrel number, bottling date, and the knob on the cork is the usual black with the Jack Daniel’s logo on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom label on the front reads RYE and has a green background where the proof and volume are listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I paid retail for my first bottle, but I didn’t. I found this bottle in Nashville, TN in June 2023. I paid about 2x retail, but it was the first one I had found, and was a very high proof at 139.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you found a bottle of the Barrel Proof Rye yet? Keep looking, it should be available pretty much anywhere you can find the Barrel Proof Tennessee Whiskey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two previous Barrel Proof Ryes released by Jack Daniel’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/TennesseeTastersBarrelProofRye&quot;&gt;Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Tasters’ Barrel Proof Rye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2020SpecialRelease&quot;&gt;2020 Jack Daniel’s Barrel Proof Rye Special Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2023&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 139.3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 750ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $65&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-is-jack-daniels-single-barrel-barrel-proof-rye-worth&quot;&gt;How Much Is Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Barrel Proof Rye Worth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Barrel Proof Rye is worth retail price. You shouldn’t really be paying more than retail for this bottle as it is a regular release. Higher proofs might draw a little more value, but not too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-of-jacks-value-assessment&quot;&gt;Collector Of Jack’s Value Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great bottle to own, go for the higher proofs you can find, or bottls with specific bottling dates that are important to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/BarrelProofRye</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/BarrelProofRye</guid>
    
    
    <category>Rye</category>
    
    <category>750ml</category>
    
    <category>Barrel Proof Rye</category>
    
    <category>Barrel Proof</category>
    
    <category>Single Barrel</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s and McLaren Racing: A Toast to High-Speed Partnership</title>
    <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;celebrating-five-years-of-collectorofjackcom&quot;&gt;Celebrating Five Years of CollectorOfJack.com&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, November 18, 2023, marks a special milestone for us at CollectorOfJack.com. It’s been exactly five years since we launched our website in its first iteration back on November 18, 2018. We’ve come a long way since then, and we’re excited to continue sharing our passion for Jack Daniel’s with you. While posts have been infrequent lately, our founder Chris Hammond is committed to ramping up the content. Expect to see more frequent updates, with the aim of bringing you new and exciting content at least once a week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-blend-of-heritage-and-high-performance&quot;&gt;A Blend of Heritage and High Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight (tomorrow morning really) is the Formula 1 race in Las Vegas, today’s post is in honor of that hopefully great event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lynchburg, Tennessee&lt;/strong&gt; – In a groundbreaking move, Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey and McLaren Racing have announced a multi-year partnership, starting in 2023. This collaboration marks the first venture of Jack Daniel’s, a brand steeped in over 155 years of whiskey crafting heritage, into the high-octane world of Formula 1 racing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img src=”/images/generated/67/f1car-800-e9a435bea.jpg” alt=”“Jack Daniel’s / McLaren F1 Car”” srcset=”/images/generated/67/f1car-200-e9a435bea.jpg 200w, /images/generated/67/f1car-400-e9a435bea.jpg 400w, /images/generated/67/f1car-800-e9a435bea.jpg 800w, /images/generated/67/f1car-1600-e9a435bea.jpg 1600w, /images/generated/67/f1car-2000-e9a435bea.jpg 2000w”&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-look-on-the-track&quot;&gt;A New Look on the Track&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s iconic branding will be prominently displayed on the nose of McLaren’s 2023 Formula 1 cars. Additionally, the brand’s logos will adorn the drivers’ overalls and the helmets of the pit crew, integrating the whiskey brand’s identity into the dynamic and globally followed sport of Formula 1 racing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-limited-edition-collectible&quot;&gt;A Limited Edition Collectible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate this partnership, a limited edition bottle of Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey has been released. This collectible bottle not only celebrates the collaboration but also honors the pioneering founders of each brand, Mr. Jack Daniel and Bruce McLaren. The bottle features the distinctive papaya colorway of McLaren, along with a customized label and packaging, making it a must-have for enthusiasts of both whiskey and motorsports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-toast-to-future-success&quot;&gt;A Toast to Future Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of a broader multi-year sponsorship agreement, this partnership aligns Jack Daniel’s—one of the world’s best-selling whiskeys—with the high-performance and international prestige of the McLaren Formula 1 team. Fans of motorsports and whiskey alike can look forward to a variety of events, media, and hospitality programs throughout the 2023 F1 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bottle-information&quot;&gt;Bottle Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from our photo gallery here the bottle and box are quite the departure from anything we’ve seen from Jack Daniel’s in the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-front-of-the-box-reads&quot;&gt;The front of the box reads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;McL X JD 2023 Edition&lt;br /&gt;
Jack Daniel’s&lt;br /&gt;
Old No. 7 Brand&lt;br /&gt;
Tennessee Sour Mash Whiskey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;McLaren Formula 1 Team&lt;br /&gt;
Jack Daniel’s Old No. 7 Brand Official Partner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-sides-of-the-box-read&quot;&gt;The sides of the box read:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;McL X JD 2023 Edition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rear-of-the-box-reads&quot;&gt;The rear of the box reads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel &amp;amp; Bruce McLaren&lt;br /&gt;
founded their brands with a pioneering spirit driven by the continuous quest for perfection.&lt;br /&gt;
Two iconic brands united in independence, living boldly, and doing it responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-front-of-the-bottle-reads&quot;&gt;The front of the bottle reads:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s&lt;br /&gt;
Old No. 7 Brand&lt;br /&gt;
Tennessee Sour Mash Whiskey&lt;br /&gt;
McL X JD 2023 Edition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-side-of-the-bottle-reads&quot;&gt;One side of the bottle reads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel &amp;amp; Bruce McLaren&lt;br /&gt;
founded their brands with a pioneering spirit driven by the continuous quest for perfection.&lt;br /&gt;
Two iconic brands united in independence, living boldly, and doing it responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-other-side-of-the-bottle-reads&quot;&gt;The other side of the bottle reads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;McLaren Formula 1 Team&lt;br /&gt;
Jack Daniel’s Old No. 7 Brand Official Partner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rear-of-the-bottle-reads&quot;&gt;The rear of the bottle reads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;McL X JD 2023 Edition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-to-find-the-jack-daniels--mclaren-racing-formula-1-2023-bottle&quot;&gt;Where to find the Jack Daniel’s / McLaren Racing Formula 1 2023 Bottle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These bottles were released in markets where Formula 1 (F1) Races happened in 2023. In the United States they could be found in Florida, Texas and Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked these bottles up in Florida on our family vacation this summer. Big shout out to the Sunshine State Squires for helping me in tracking them down while in town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2023&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 80&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 1L&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $59&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-is-jack-daniels--mclaren-racing-formula-1-worth&quot;&gt;How Much Is Jack Daniel’s / McLaren Racing Formula 1 Worth?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find it in one of the states that it is sold, definitely don’t pay more than retail. If you’re shopping elsewhere be prepared to pay a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-of-jacks-value-assessment&quot;&gt;Collector Of Jack’s Value Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the packaging for these bottles is special, the juice is regular Jack Daniel’s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsMcLaren</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsMcLaren</guid>
    
    
    <category>McLaren</category>
    
    <category>2023</category>
    
    <category>Box</category>
    
    <category>1L</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s Twice Barreled American Single Malt 2022 Special Release</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I’ve blogged about a real bottle, that doesn’t mean I haven’t been collecting. I simply got it in my head that I needed the perfect backdrop for my photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we have the 2022 Special Release from Jack Daniels: Jack Daniels 2022 Special Release Twice Barreled American Single Malt. This is a Single Malt, I believe a first from Jack Daniel’s. It was then aged in Oloroso Sherry barrels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front of the bottle reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Neck Label: 2022 Special Release&lt;br /&gt;
Label: Uniquely Crafted Handmade Barrels&lt;br /&gt;
Twice Barreled Special Release American Single Malt&lt;br /&gt;
American Single Malt Whiskey Oloroso Sherry Cask Finished&lt;br /&gt;
Crafted from 100% malted barley twice barreled for a complex taste &amp;amp; bottled straight from the finest Oloroso sherry casks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side labels read:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Limited Bottle No. ASM-29592&lt;br /&gt;
This special release series highlights the Jack Daniel Distillery’s Innovation. Crafted from 100% malted barley, matured first in new American charred oak barrels and then in the finest Oloroso Sherry casks, we extend this one-of-a-kind craftsmanship to you.&lt;br /&gt;
Processed using minimum filtration to sustain its unique flavor profile. Sediment may occur over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-oloroso-sherry&quot;&gt;What is Oloroso Sherry?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oloroso Sherry Cask are whisky casks which have been previously held Oloroso Sherry. Oloroso Sherry is a type of fortified wine produced near the city of Jerez de la Frontera in Andalusia, Spain. The Sherry Triangle produces wines which have been ‘fortified’ with a higher alcohol strength in order to prevent yeast growth and bottled under the official name of Jerez-Xérès-Sherry. There is something of a manufactured misconception, that the casks used at these bodegas are the same used for whisky maturation however this is not the case. Oloroso sherry casks are more commonly known as sherry butts within the whisky industry. - WhiskeyPedia https://whiskipedia.com/fundamentals/oloroso-sherry-casks/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update-november-2023&quot;&gt;Update November 2023:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite bottles of Jack Daniel’s. I ended up opening it with some buddies earlier this year and the flavor is just amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can get one, I highly recommend it. For a while they were going 250-300 on secondary, but I believe they dropped a bit since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2022&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 106.6&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 700ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $79&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-much-is-jack-daniels-twice-barreled-heritage-barrel-rye-worth&quot;&gt;How Much Is Jack Daniel’s Twice Barreled Heritage Barrel Rye Worth?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondary for this bottle started out really high, north of $250, but fell towards the end of 2022, with it being found for around $200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;collector-of-jacks-value-assessment&quot;&gt;Collector Of Jack’s Value Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t spend more then $225 for a bottle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledAmericanMalt</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledAmericanMalt</guid>
    
    
    <category>Heritage Barrel</category>
    
    <category>Heritage</category>
    
    <category>Twice Barreled</category>
    
    <category>Single Malt</category>
    
    <category>Special Release</category>
    
    <category>700ml</category>
    
    <category>2022</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s life story, according to ChatGPT</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months I’ve been playing with ChatGPT. I figured I should give it a shot at writing the life story of Jack Daniel’s. I’m not sure if it’s 100% accurate, but it certainly hits most of the points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prompt&quot;&gt;Prompt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the life story of Jack Daniel? Be sure to include information Nearest Green.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;response&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel was an American distiller and businessman who founded the Jack Daniel’s Tennessee whiskey distillery. His life story is one of perseverance, ingenuity, and hard work, and it is also deeply connected to the story of Nearest Green, an African American distiller who played a significant role in the development of the Jack Daniel’s brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel was born in 1850 in Lynchburg, Tennessee. His exact birthdate is unknown as birth records were not kept in his area at the time. He was the youngest of ten children, and his parents were of Scottish and Irish descent. His father died when he was young, and he grew up working on his family’s farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he was 13, Jack ran away from home and was taken in by a local preacher, Dan Call. Call owned a distillery and taught Jack the art of making whiskey. After a few years, Jack left to start his own distillery with his mentor’s help. They called their operation “Call and Daniel’s,” and it quickly became successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1884, Jack bought out his partner and renamed the distillery “Jack Daniel’s.” He perfected his recipe for Tennessee whiskey, using a unique charcoal mellowing process that gave the whiskey a smoother flavor. His whiskey became famous, and he won numerous awards for its quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for many years, the role that Nearest Green played in the development of the Jack Daniel’s brand was largely unknown. Green was a slave on a farm owned by Dan Call, and he was also a skilled distiller. It is believed that Green taught Jack Daniel how to make whiskey using the charcoal mellowing process, which became a defining characteristic of the Jack Daniel’s brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Civil War, Green continued to work for Call as a free man and was eventually hired by Jack Daniel as the distillery’s first head distiller. Green taught his techniques to other workers at the distillery, and his legacy lived on long after his death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, many people see Green as an important figure in the history of American whiskey and an example of the resilience and ingenuity of the African American community. In recent years, the Jack Daniel’s distillery has taken steps to honor Green’s legacy, including unveiling a memorial to him in 2016 and establishing the Nearest Green Foundation to promote diversity in the whiskey industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s whiskey remains one of the most popular whiskey brands in the world, with its distinctive black and white label recognized across the globe. The distillery still operates in Lynchburg, Tennessee, and attracts visitors from around the world who want to learn more about the history of this iconic brand and the important role that Nearest Green played in its development.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsLifeStory</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsLifeStory</guid>
    
    
    <category>History</category>
    
    <category>ChatGPT</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>How Much Is My Jack Daniels Collection Worth?</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;We get asked this question a lot.  “How much is my Jack Daniels collection worth?”  The answer is, it depends.  There are a lot of factors that go into determining the value of a collection.  We will try to cover some things, but likely not all, that go into evaluating a liquor collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-you-collecting&quot;&gt;What are you collecting?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you collecting just Jack Daniel’s, or do you collect other bourbons and whiskeys as well?&lt;/strong&gt; What you focus on collecting will be important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have lots of non-bottle items in your collection?&lt;/strong&gt; I have a few things, a couple of barrels, a yard stick, a bat, and a variety of smaller items, couple of signs, but the majority of my collection is (and almost always will be) bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been collecting?&lt;/strong&gt; Many Jack Daniel’s collections have been put together over decades. I personally have been collecting since around 1998, though early on I wasn’t necessarily collecting, I managed to save a lot of things over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much do you think you have invested in your collection?&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously, think about how much you’ve spent over the years. I can guess what I’ve spent over the years, though with my inventory sheet I have a pretty good idea of what I’ve spent in the last 12-24 months. Going forward, keep track of your purchases (see inventory below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;condition&quot;&gt;Condition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What condition are your bottles in?&lt;/strong&gt; Is the glass clean? Have they been regularly dusted? If you haven’t dusted them lately, do they clean up when you do dust them? You can often times clean them with a solution, but be careful not to damage labels, tax stamps, or seals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the labels intact?&lt;/strong&gt; Have they been damaged? Are they faded? Do they have any rips or tears in the label? Is the label crooked? Does the label have any stains? All of these things can impact the value of a bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the bottles full?&lt;/strong&gt; If they are unopened, and full, they are worth more. If the bottle has been opened, than you can’t prove the contents are legitimate, there are definitely people out there who fake bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there any leakage?&lt;/strong&gt; If the bottle has leaked, the value of the bottle might be reduced, but this can actually be fairly common for older bottles and might have little impact on the value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do the corks look good?&lt;/strong&gt; Are they in good shape? Have you regularly rotated the bottles so that the corks don’t dry out? If they dry out, they can fall apart and fall into the bottle.  This can decrease the value of the bottle and the contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A&lt;strong&gt;re the seals intact?&lt;/strong&gt; If the seals have been tampered with, the value of the bottle can be greatly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a tax stamp?&lt;/strong&gt; Older bottles oftentimes have tax stamps, they can actually allow you to get a date for the bottle. Newer bottles don’t have tax stamps, so you have to look at other things to try to determine age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any chips or cracks in the bottles?&lt;/strong&gt; If so, the value will be impacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;age&quot;&gt;Age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How old are the bottles?&lt;/strong&gt; Do you know how to tell? Sometimes you can figure out the age based on a tax stamp, some times you can figure out the age based on a marking on the bottle? Often times with Jack Daniel’s bottles there is a number on the bottom of the bottle to determine the year. With JD Single Barrel products you can determine when it was bottled based on the label around the neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are they from a limited release?&lt;/strong&gt; Jack Daniel’s has been doing special bottles and releases for decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rarity&quot;&gt;Rarity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many bottles were produced?&lt;/strong&gt; That will completely vary based on the release, each release is definitely different, and sometimes, for example the Eric Church bottles there were actually multiple releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-can-i-sell-my-collection&quot;&gt;Where can I sell my collection?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That one can be a tricky question to answer, there are a lot of factors to consider.
&lt;strong&gt;Where do you live?&lt;/strong&gt; 
Do you know what the laws are around selling alcohol in your state?&lt;br /&gt;
Do you want to sell them all at once or one at a time?&lt;br /&gt;
Do you want to sell them to a private collector or a retailer? 
If you are in our around St. Louis (6 hour radius) and interested in selling, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;be sure to reach out to me&lt;/a&gt;. I might be interested.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/HowMuchIsMyJackDanielsCollectionWorth</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/HowMuchIsMyJackDanielsCollectionWorth</guid>
    
    
    <category>Collection</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Pre-release Jack Daniel&apos;s 2022 Special Release Twice Barreled American Single Malt</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/TwiceBarreledAmericanMalt&quot;&gt;Updated post after actual release&lt;/a&gt;
The 2022 Special Release for Jack Daniel’s should be hitting shelves very soon! We don’t have a bottle yet, but wanted to highlight what you can expect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s Twice Barreled Special Release American Single Malt, an Oloroso sherry-finished whiskey made from 100% malted barley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This special release series highlights the Jack Daniel Distillery’s innovation. Crafted from 100% malted barley, matured first in new American charred oak barrels and then in the finest Oloroso sherry casks, we extend this one-of-a-kind craftsmanship to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Oloroso Sherry?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oloroso Sherry Cask are whisky casks which have been previously held Oloroso Sherry. Oloroso Sherry is a type of fortified wine produced near the city of Jerez de la Frontera in Andalusia, Spain. The Sherry Triangle produces wines which have been ‘fortified’ with a higher alcohol strength in order to prevent yeast growth and bottled under the official name of Jerez-Xérès-Sherry. There is something of a manufactured misconception, that the casks used at these bodegas are the same used for whisky maturation however this is not the case. Oloroso sherry casks are more commonly known as sherry butts within the whisky industry. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://whiskipedia.com/fundamentals/oloroso-sherry-casks/&quot;&gt;WhiskeyPedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2022&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 108&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 750ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $??&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledMaltPrerelease</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/TwiceBarreledMaltPrerelease</guid>
    
    
    <category>Heritage Barrel</category>
    
    <category>Heritage</category>
    
    <category>Twice Barreled</category>
    
    <category>Single Malt</category>
    
    <category>Special Release</category>
    
    <category>700ml</category>
    
    <category>2022</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Two new Tennessee Tasters bottles from Jack Daniel&apos;s</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Hot off the presses Jack Daniel’s has just announced two new bottles in the Tennessee Taster’s series, and is now calling them Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series Toasted Barrel Finished Rye&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series Toasted Maple Barrel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about them from Jack Daniel’s social media:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A few years ago we began a special line of experimental whiskeys available only in Tennessee now called our Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series to give us an opportunity to celebrate, and share some of the special whiskeys that we’ve crafted. This October our eighth and ninth selections will be available – Jack Daniel’s Toasted Maple Barrel Rye and Toasted Barrel Finished Rye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s Assistant Distiller Lexie Phillips has teamed up with her husband, Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Processing Operator and taster Josh Phillips to create two new offerings that truly stand out and reflect Jack Daniel’s spirit of craft and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series Toasted Barrel Finished Rye&lt;/em&gt; was selected by Lexie Phillips and is a Straight Tennessee Rye Whiskey bottled at 101 proof (50.5% abv) with notes of caramel and toasted oak with layers of rye spice, molasses, and dark chocolate imparting a full body mouth feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Daniel’s Distillery Series Toasted Maple Barrel&lt;/em&gt; Rye was selected by Josh Phillips and is a Straight Tennessee Rye Whiskey bottled at 101 proof (50.5% abv) featuring a sweet aroma of honey and vanilla with notes of maple, raisins, pralines, and butterscotch with a lasting finish of toasted marshmallow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These two special bottles will be available select stores in Tennessee including the White Rabbit Bottle Shop* at the Jack Daniel Distillery starting this October for around $41.99 for a 375 ml bottle. We hope if you have a chance to try them that you’ll let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;*These bottles are not yet in stock at the White Rabbit Bottle Shop but will be available soon. We will make a post when the White Rabbit has these bottles in stock. If you’d like to give them a call, you can reach them at 931-759-6310.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These bottles are available only in Tennessee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2022&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 101&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 375ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $41&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/October2022TennesseeTasters</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/October2022TennesseeTasters</guid>
    
    
    <category>Tasters Series</category>
    
    <category>Tennessee Tasters</category>
    
    <category>TN Tasters</category>
    
    <category>Toasted Barrel</category>
    
    <category>Rye</category>
    
    <category>Maple</category>
    
    </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Jack Daniel&apos;s Small Batch Coy Hill</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Hot off the presses and hot to the tongue, Jack Daniel’s has announced that this Friday starting at 8am at the White Rabbit Bottle Shop you can get the new Small Batch Coy Hill 375ml bottle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some of the press I’ve been able to find:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;a very limited release small batch whiskey that we’ll be offering in Tennessee this summer, our Jack Daniel’s Small Batch Special Release Coy Hill High Proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Back in 2021 when we were bottling our Single Barrel Special Release Coy Hill High Proof, we found around 55 barrels where the Angel’s Share was so high the liquid inside could not be bottled as Single Barrel selections. When we found these barrels in our Coy Hill barrelhouses, we immediately knew we had something special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jack Daniel’s Small Batch Special Release Coy Hill High Proof has an aroma of burnt sugar, cooked fruit, and oak with notes of rich molasses and concentrated barrel spice with bold oak. It finishes long and full with layers of char, dried fruit, and caramel. Matured in the highest reaches of barrelhouses on Coy Hill, the highest elevation at the Jack Daniel Distillery, this Tennessee Whiskey is bottled at proof points ranging from 143.6 - 155.1. It is the highest proof whiskey that we’ve released to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 375 ml bottles will be available in very limited quantities in Tennessee and at the White Rabbit Bottle Shop at the Jack Daniel Distillery with a suggested retail price of $55. The White Rabbit Bottle Shop will begin sales on Friday, July 1 at 8:00 a.m. There will be a limit of one bottle per visitor. We hope if you have a chance to try it, you’ll let us know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Due to the high barrel strength, the bottle should remain upright at all times unless pouring into a glass to enjoy. •&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still trying to figure out if I can get over to Lynchburg this week, unlikely with such short notice, but who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsSpecialReleaseCoyHillHighProof&quot;&gt;Don’t forget to read about the 2021 Special Release Coy Hill High Proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release:&lt;/strong&gt; 2022&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Proof:&lt;/strong&gt; 143.6-155.1&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Size:&lt;/strong&gt; 375ml&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $55&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <link>https://collectorofjack.com/SmallBatchCoyHill2022</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://collectorofjack.com/SmallBatchCoyHill2022</guid>
    
    
    <category>Coy Hill</category>
    
    <category>Special Release</category>
    
    <category>High Proof</category>
    
    <category>375ml</category>
    
    </item>
  
  </channel>
</rss>
