<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-03T04:53:19+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CollectorOfJack.com</title><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Bicentennial</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsTennesseeBicentennial" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Bicentennial" /><published>2020-09-02T23:40:40+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T23:40:40+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsTennesseeBicentennial</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In 1995 Jack Daniel’s released a 750ml bottle to celebrate the State of Tennessee’s Bicentennial for the year 1996. This replica of the 1896 Centennial bottle that Jack Daniel produced in limited quantities was available in in the US, and in international markets in a 700ml size.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Eric Church Single Barrel 2020</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/EricChurchSingleBarrel2020" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Eric Church Single Barrel 2020" /><published>2020-08-31T23:45:40+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T23:45:40+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/EricChurchSingleBarrel2020</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In July/August 2020 Jack Daniel’s released the 2020 version of the Eric Church Single Barrel Select bottle, a follow on release after their 2019 Eric Church Double Down Tour Single Barrel. This year’s bottle is a beautiful opaque black with a black and gold label. It came with a paper hang tag, also in black and gold.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tennessee Tasters’ Barrel Proof Rye</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/TennesseeTastersBarrelProofRye" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tennessee Tasters’ Barrel Proof Rye" /><published>2020-08-30T22:32:40+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T22:32:40+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/TennesseeTastersBarrelProofRye</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In July of 2019 Jack Daniel’s released the fourth bottle in their Tennessee Tasters’ series, Barrel Proof Rye, Straight Tennessee Rye Whiskey.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daytona Bike Week 2020 Collectors Bottle</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/DaytonaBikeWeek2020" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daytona Bike Week 2020 Collectors Bottle" /><published>2020-04-16T04:26:58+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-16T04:26:58+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/DaytonaBikeWeek2020</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">Last fall I discovered that there are Facebook groups dedicated to Jack Daniel’s. I started following The Jack Cave, with Sue Scheel Clark. One a post there one day she mentioned the Sunshine State Squires and Collectors Facebook Group out of Florida, and that they were putting together some special edition bottles, and had previously done a few bottles as well. The first bottle that I learned about is one I hope to write about in the next week or two, as I don’t have it yet, but today I received my first bottle from the group.This bottle was put together for the 2020 Daytona Beach Bike Week. The bottle is a single barrel selection chosen by the group, and contains a number of very cool things! The first, most noticeable item is the custom sleeve, with a photoshopped picture combining Easy Rider and the ocean. It also contains a hang tag reading “Daytona Beach Bike Week 2020”.It contains a sticker, a coaster, and a custom coin, along with an etched bottle.The front of the coin reads the same as the logo on the sleeve:Daytona Beach, Florida79th Bike WeekWorld’s Largest Motorcycle Event2020The etched bottle reads the same as the coaster, and the back of the coin:Daytona Beach Bike WeekRide ResponsiblyBottles &amp;amp; Throttles Don’t Mix2020I ended up ordering two of these bottles, and 3 extra sleeves. As I’ve gotten into the various Facebook groups I’ve seen these custom bottles and sleeves that have “scenes”, and when you have multiple boxes next to each other you can see the full scene, you can see this in the photos below as I have a shot of one of the sleeves fully spread out.I look forward to partaking in future bottle sales that these groups do!Bottled: March 10, 2020Barrel Number: 20-01418Rick No.: L-17Release: March 2020Proof: 94Size: 750mlPrice: $75/bottle</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first whiskey tasting event</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/my-first-whiskey-tasting-event" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first whiskey tasting event" /><published>2020-02-13T05:01:49+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T05:01:49+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/my-first-whiskey-tasting-event</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been threatening for months that I was going to have a whiskey tasting event, this past Friday I finally did it. This post contains an overview of how I planned, how the event went and what lessons learned for future events.PlanningThe biggest hurdle to this event was just picking a date, for months I haven’t been able to get a date on the calendar, so in late January I threw one up (February 7th) and created a private Facebook event with info. I then sent the invite out to a small group of friends, some of which I had been talking about the event with for months. In the Facebook I included a list of various bottles that I had acquired for the purpose of drinking over the past year, including selections of Jack Daniel’s, and non Jack Daniel’s bottles. I also requested that everyone bring an unopened bottle of their own, an if they felt like leaving it afterward they could. I ended up extending the invites out to 11 people, 8 of whom were able to make it. As I neared the date I started prepping some things.I cleaned all my whiskey glasses, and wine glasses (not for use, but because they hadn’t been washed in…. years) I purchased some new tasting glasses, 8 of them, shaped like Glencairn glasses, but not the brand.I did a little reading on how best to host a whiskey tasting. (Google it) I posted a link to an article about “infinity” bottles, or the idea of filling up a decanter with a variety of different whiskeys, either when a bottle is opened, or as a bottle nears it’s completion. I suggested everyone bring a decanter and we could see about filling them up.I changed my mind about everyone bringing a decanter, and decided that I was going to buy some moonshine bottles and personalize them for the event (see the photos below, I think they turned out great).Made a selection of ice for the event, for anyone who wanted ice in their glasses (not everyone did).At 5pm that evening I headed to the local grocery store, hoping to score some snacks, and hoping to score some whiskey for the night. In the local Bourbon Facebook group there were substantiated rumors that you could find some Weller’s Reserve and Eagle Rare at the Dierberg’s around town, so I headed to the Wildwood location with hopes of finding one or both. I was able to fill up the cart with snacks, and a bottle of the Dierberg’s Single Barrel selection of the Eagle Rare.Final prep for the night of including getting the dining room table extended and bringing extra chairs up from the basement. I also picked up some crackers and pizza bites to warm up, in case anyone was hungry for something. The pizza bites didn’t last an hour.Event ExperienceCome the night of I was ready about an hour before the scheduled start time, so I sat down to read my copy of The Whiskey Advocate that mysteriously showed up in my mailbox a week ago. When the first guests showed up we took a seat in the kitchen and caught up a bit waiting for the rest of the crew to arrive.As everyone showed up, all bringing a bottle of their choice, I gave a tour of the basement where I keep my “undrinkables”, my Jack Daniel’s collection. From there we took our seats at the dining room table, the location for the tasting, and I passed out the custom decanters. Everyone got to choose a glass from the table, and then I tried to determine what we would start with. My original list on the invite had probably 12 different bottles of mine that I wanted to use, but I quickly realized that wasn’t going to be realistic, so we started with the guest provided bottles and mixed in 4 or 5 of mine throughout the night.Everyone got a “dram”, a small pour, supposed to be 3/4 of an OZ, but unmeasured on my pours. We went in the following order:Eagle Rare (90 Proof) Knob Creek Smoked Maple (90 proof)Tamdhu Scotch (96 Proof)New Riff Kentucky Straight Rye Bottled In Bond (100 proof)Breckenridge Bourbon Whiskey (86 proof)Sons of Erin Irish Whiskey (92 Proof)Woodford Reserve (90.4 Proof)Whistle Pig Farmstock Rye (86 Proof)Blanton’s (93 Proof)Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel 2019 (100 Proof)Jack Daniel’s No. 27 Gold (80 proof)George Dickel Bottled in Bond (100 proof)Outside of the tasting a few of us tried Bruichladdich The Classic Laddie, a scottish barley, which we mostly immediately regretted. We had quite the variety of things to choose from on our first tasting. In the future we’ll have to decide if we want to try that many in one go again or not. Overall consensus was that the Blanton’s was the best. After that it was mixed, but I think the Jack Daniel’s No. 27 Gold was extra smooth and drinkable. Definitely glad we cracked that one open.My buddy who brought the Whistle Pig Farmstock Rye brought me another bottle, we didn't open it, but I did get to keep it. It is a 100 Proof bottle of The Legendary Hatfield &amp; McCoy Family Brand Whiskey. I spent a few minutes looking online, and no proof of this bottle's existance can be found (you can find the 80 proof version, but I don't think 100 proof ever went to retail), how cool is that?Lessons LearnedOne, have fun. This was a great damn time. Invite some good friends, and invite some people you might not know that well. If you can get everyone to bring/leave a bottle, you can build up your collection! Be prepared, there was no way I had enough glasses for 9 people to try 12 different drinks. What we ended up doing was putting a bowl on each end of the table, and a pitcher of water. Rinsing the glasses out in between drams. This worked out pretty well, though I’m sure purists might cringe at the idea.Doing an infinite bottle/decanter might not make sense at a tasting like this, maybe that comes with some sort of a bring a bottle/trade pours type of thing.If I do this again in the future, no, not if, WHEN I do this again in the future, I will have to come up with another parting gift for everyone who attends.I am already trying to figure out when the next one is, likely in April 2020. Thinking I’ve got enough special edition Jack Daniel’s bottles we can crack open (in my drinkable selection) that we might just do a Night Dedicated To Jack Daniels.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Before and After Release</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/before-after" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Before and After Release" /><published>2019-12-29T05:11:58+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-29T05:11:58+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/before-after</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In the fall of 2019 rumors started swirling online of a new release available at the White Rabbit Bottleshop in Lynchburg, of a Before and After set. Two bottles of unmatured Old No. 7, one BEFORE Charcoal Mellowing and one AFTER Charcoal Mellowing, along with a small bottle of Hard Sugar Maple Charcoal in between the two bottles. The BEFORE bottle on the left, the AFTER on the right.It ends up the package was exclusive to Tennessee, and could be found at a variety of locations around the state. I lined up a set with a local in Lynchburg, and planned to get it in the mail, trading for a Scenes of Lynchburg series bottle, but got cold feet before shipping and ended up committing to the other party that I would trade in person next time I make it to Lynchburg.In November I made a trek south from St. Louis down to Memphis and picked up two packages of the Before and After set, maintaining my intention of getting the third set mentioned above.The bottles and charcoal come in a black box, the bottles with a white label with black text. The bottles are 375ml, with whiskey aged only one day.This set has a lot of writing on it, so I am not going to transcribe all of that writing this time around, but will include a couple of interesting bits.Tasting Directions1) Pour an ounce of our before charcoal mellowing whiskey into a tasking glass. Without mellowing, it’s nose has extra cereal notes and its taste is more harsh and oily in character.2) Pour an ounce of our after charcoal mellowing whiskey into a second glass. Because this whiskey has been mellowed drop by drop, you’ll notice its nose and taste is smoother and cleaner. It is absent the grainy character of the before mellowing Jack Daniel’s.One last thing, the bottle mentions a URL, jackdaniels.com/BEFORE-AFTER but as of December 28th, 2019, the URL only leads to a 404 page.Release: 2019Proof: 80Size: 375ml (x2)Price: $29.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 Jack Daniel’s Holiday Countdown Calendar</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/2019AdventCalendar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 Jack Daniel’s Holiday Countdown Calendar" /><published>2019-12-19T16:41:16+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T16:41:16+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/2019AdventCalendar</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">For 2019 Jack Daniel’s has brought their holiday (advent) calendar across the pond to the United States! They’ve also made it available elsewhere around the globe this year as well, where I believe primarily over the past couple of years it was only available in the UK (I could be wrong on that fact).I spent quite a bit of time this fall trying to find this calendar in the St. Louis market, but no stores that I talked to knew anything about it, and from what I can tell no one in the St. Louis market got any in for sale. I ended up driving to Memphis a few weeks back and picked up 3 for myself. 1 to open (see my instagram feed for the daily opening), 1 to keep, and 1 to have as a tradeable item in the future.The countdown calendar comes with 20 50ML bottles, and 4 shot glasses. The bottles are a mix of Tennessee Honey, Old #7, Tennessee Fire, Gentleman Jack, Single Barrel Select and Rye.The front of the box readsJack Daniel Distillery Lynchburg Tenn.Holiday Countdown CalendarThe back has the logos, and a description of each of the various libations along with Happy Holidays from Our Family to YoursIn Lynchburg, Tennessee, the holidays are about traditions old and new. While old traditions warm the heart, there’s something special about starting a new one. We hope that as you open a new calendar door, you’ll share a toast with the folks closest to you.Each day, the 1st through the 24th, has a separate door that you open to find the present for the day. In the first week or so you'll find three shot glasses, the fourth one comes later in the month. The doors can be a little difficult to open without causing bending of the cardboard, but if you're careful it can be done. \tIf you can get your hands on one of these countdown calendars, enjoy! Overseas they can be found in a variety of locations at a discount as the month is half over, here in the US though they appear to still be hard to find.Happy Holidays!Release: 2019Proof: VariesSize: 20 x 50mlPrice: $89.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Apple</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/TennesseeApple" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Apple" /><published>2019-11-26T15:12:18+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-26T15:12:18+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/TennesseeApple</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">With the release of Jack Honey and Fire over the past 10 years, it was time for Jack Daniel’s to catch the apple train and release their own Tennessee Apple Liqueur. I was able to get some here in Missouri earlier this fall from lukasliquorstl.com.The 750ml bottle comes in the usual Jack Daniel’s shape with a green gold and white label. The front of the bottle reads:Jack Daniel’s Original RecipeTennessee AppleFinely CraftedApple Liqueur Blended with Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey35% ALC. By Vol. (70 Proof)One side of the bottle reads:Smooth FlavorTennessee Apple has the distinct character of Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey coupled with crisp green apple for a fresh &amp;amp; rewarding taste.Enjoy ChilledCaramel Colored The other side reads:Jack Daniel’s CharacterLynchburg, TennClassic Green AppleCrisp &amp;amp; FreshExceptionally SmoothHighest QualityThe back reads:Distilled &amp;amp; Bottled by Jack Daniel Distillery Lynchburg, Tenn USAThe bottle can be found at retailers everywhere, and as I understand it, is around for a while, so it shouldn’t be too hard to track down.Release: 2019Proof: 70Size: 750mlPrice: $22.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel 2019</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/HeritageBarrel2019" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel 2019" /><published>2019-11-11T03:51:06+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-11T03:51:06+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/HeritageBarrel2019</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">Back again for 2019 is the Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Heritage Barrel. In 2018 JD had a special release for this limited bottling, consisting of a rumored two hundred barrels, bottled in September 2018.For 2019, Jack Daniels has once again released Heritage Barrel, this time, aging it 1 year more, and the rumors in collecting communities say that they bottled fewer barrels this year. Bottles were bottled on both 9/9/2019 and 9/10/2019, though rumors also say that there were fewer bottles bottled on the 10th.Finding a bottle this year was difficult to say the least. I spent weeks driving to liquor stores, calling liquor stores, and looking online, to see if I could find a bottle. I got the run around at the Chesterfield Total Wine. Depending on who I asked I was told it hadn’t come yet, or that it came weeks ago and was already gone.Lukas Liquors in Ellisville, MO came through though. They were super responsive on twitter, and super helpful when I was in the store multiple times inquiring about the bottle. They reached out via DM on twitter on Thursday, saying that the bottles had arrived and they were holding one for me! I took off at lunch and went to pick it up, not wanting to risk the bottle being sold to someone else!The bottle itself doesn’t vary much, if at all, from the 2018 release, so we won’t bother covering all the details again, you can check out the 2018 post for those.I ended up paying $80/each for my two bottles. Wait, what? Yeah, two bottles. Last year I only found one, and didn’t get to crack it open. This year I got two, with the idea that I’ll be tasting one of these. Release: Fall 2019Proof: 100Size: 750ml</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Eric Church (2019)</title><link href="https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsEricChurch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel Eric Church (2019)" /><published>2019-11-07T17:28:17+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T17:28:17+00:00</updated><id>https://collectorofjack.com/JackDanielsEricChurch</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">This post is for the 2019 version of the Eric Church bottle, stay tuned for information if we get a 2020 bottle! As part of Eric Church’s Double Down US Tour Jack Daniels teamed up with the country artist for a limited edition single barrel bottle. The bottle appears to be a pretty standard single barrel bottle, ours was bottled on 12/19/2018, it came with a hang metal Eric Church Chief tag with JD Limited Edition on the back of the tag (see photos below).The bottle came with/in a somewhat custom single barrel box. The front reads with the normal single barrel select branding, but has a black silhouette of the bottle with a rendering of the Eric Church / Chief tag.The back of the box reads:Music and friendships were always important to Mr. Jack. That’s why we are proud to offer this limited edition Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel package celebrating our longstanding relationship with Eric Church. Not only is Eric a Friend of Jack, but he shared Jack Daniel’s spirit of community. In honor of that spirit we are making a donation in support of the “Chief Cares Fund,” a non-profit created by Eric and his wife, Katherine in 2013 to impact lives around the globe and in our own neighborhoods.You can still find the bottle online at some retailers. Release: 2019Proof: 94Size: 750mlPrice: $65+</summary></entry></feed>