<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-04T13:04:31-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CollectorOfJack.com</title><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Fire Updated Bottle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/JackDanielsTennesseeFire2020" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Fire Updated Bottle" /><published>2020-09-03T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/JackDanielsTennesseeFire2020</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">Somehow I haven’t blogged about the Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Fire, and here we are with a second iteration of the bottle already! Maybe soon we’ll get some pictures of the original bottle, for now we’ll cover the newly designed bottle that was released in 2019 and most markets in 2020. Tennessee Fire was the second offering of flavored liqueurs from Jack Daniel’s, first was Honey, and third was Tennessee Apple. Changes from the Original Recipe This bottle is different from the original Cinnamon Fire release, the color of the label has changed, and the wording Original Recipe has been replaced with Cinnamon Spice. Front Label The label on the bottle is red, with gold and black trim, along with white and gold text. Jack Daniel’s Cinnamon Spice Tennessee Fire Finely Crafted Cinnamon Liqueur Blended with Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey Side Labels Jack Daniel’s Character Lynchburg, Tenn Spiced Cinnamon Warm Finish Exceptionally Smooth Highest Quality Bold Flavor Our Tennessee Fire has the distinctive taste of Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey and the Warmth of Cinnamon for a unique and rewarding taste. Enjoy Chilled Tennessee Fire Thoughts If you haven’t tried Tennessee Fire, you should. It’s hot, cinnamon, but worth a taste. I prefer it straight, though chilling it before consumption, or with some ice works as well. You can find it at most retailers, nothing special about it from a purchasing perspective. Specs Release: 2020 Proof: 70 Size: 750ml Price: $19.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Master Distiller Jeff Arnett</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MasterDistillerJeffArnett" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Master Distiller Jeff Arnett" /><published>2020-09-03T05:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-03T05:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MasterDistillerJeffArnett</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">September is the accepted Birth Month of Jack Daniel’s, so every September there is a month long celebration with photos and stories that are posted online. This month however is a little different, it was announced yesterday that Master Distiller Jeff Arnett will be stepping down at the end of September 2020, and leaving Jack Daniel’s. No further details have been provided, is he retiring, going somewhere else? Jeff was brought on to replace Jimmy ‘Bobo’ Bedford in 2008 and was listed as the 7th Master Distiller, Number 7, for this iconic brand. There is debate nowadays as to weather he is actually number 7, or number 8, as the Jack Daniel’s brand starts to recognize Nathan ‘Nearest’ Green and his importance to the history of the business. That doesn’t take anything away from what Jeff has done for the brand in his time. He has brought a new mashbill to Jack Daniel’s with the introduction of their Rye products, as well as expanding the offerings of the brand with the flavored offerings of Honey, Fire and Apple. I was fortunate to get to say hello to Jeff back in December 2014 during the bottle signing event for the Holiday Select release, the last time JD has offered that release. The photos on this post are from that event. A Letter to Jeff Dear Jeff, Thanks for everything you’ve done for the Jack Daniel’s Brand in your 12 years as Master Distiller and 20 years as an employee. Best wishes with whatever the future brings you. Anytime you are in the St. Louis area, feel free to swing by for a drink! -Collector Of Jack Who will take Jeff’s Place and be the next Master Distiller? Word is that Brown Foreman will make the announcement for Jeff’s replacement in the future. I think Chris Fletcher, Assistant Master Distiller, is obviously a potential pick, but he’s rather young, will that play into the decision? Will the brand try to fill the role with someone who provides more diversity to the brand? In today’s day and age, I would assume that BF is looking at this as an option. I don’t know that I have an opinion as to which direction they should go, but I look forward to following along as the brand continues to mature and age.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Bicentennial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/JackDanielsTennesseeBicentennial" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Bicentennial" /><published>2020-09-02T18:40:40-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T18:40:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/JackDanielsTennesseeBicentennial</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In 1995 Jack Daniel’s released a 750ml bottle to celebrate the State of Tennessee’s Bicentennial for the year 1996. This replica of the 1896 Centennial bottle that Jack Daniel produced in limited quantities was available in in the US, and in international markets in a 700ml size. The front of the bottle reads: Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Bicentennial Whiskey 1796-1996 The hang tag reads: In honor of our state’s 200th birthday, we’d like to share a simple salute with you. Our Tennessee Bicentennial Bottle is a replica of the Centennial Decanter Mr. Jack designed back in 1896. And, like the decanter the whiskey inside has remained true to the original except for one special difference-it’s bottled at 96 proof in honor of this bicentennial year. Here’s to the enduring spirit of Tennessee tradition. 1796-1996 Where did you get it? I got this bottle from my father. Where he got it, we aren’t quite sure. It has never been opened, still had the hang tag on it, and he has no other collectible bottles. For as long as I can remember, my dad has always drank Jack and Coke, almost ritually one every night after work. Never more, never less. It is possible that he purchased it back in 1995, but my guess is that he likely recieved it as a retirement gift from someone when he retired from the Air Force in 1998. Where To Buy You might be able to find the bottle online, though prices will very wildly. Anywhere from a couple hundred dollars, to wayyyyy more than that. Release: 1995 Proof: 96 Size: 750ml Price: $Unknown</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Eric Church Single Barrel 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/EricChurchSingleBarrel2020" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Eric Church Single Barrel 2020" /><published>2020-08-31T18:45:40-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-31T18:45:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/EricChurchSingleBarrel2020</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In July/August 2020 Jack Daniel’s released the 2020 version of the Eric Church Single Barrel Select bottle, a follow on release after their 2019 Eric Church Double Down Tour Single Barrel. This year’s bottle is a beautiful opaque black with a black and gold label. It came with a paper hang tag, also in black and gold. The front of the label, and the front of the hang tag reads: Special Edition Jack Daniel’s Eric Church Single Barrel Select Tennessee Whiskey The rear of the hang tag reads: Music and friendships were always important to Mr. Jack. That’s why we are proud to offer this special edition Jack Daniel’s single barrel package celebrating our longstanding friendship with Eric Church who shares Jack Daniel’s spirit of Community. In 2013 Eric and his wife, Katherine, created the non-profit “Chief Cares Fund” to impact lives around the globe and in our own neighborhoods. For more information go to: www.ericchurch.com/chief-cares The rear of the bottle reads: This special edition Jack Daniel’s single barrel package celebrates our friendship with Eric Church. Master Distiller, Jeff Arnett hand-selected this 94 proof single barrel Tennessee Whiskey according to Eric Church’s favorite Jack Daniel’s taste profile. In the photos below you might notice a metal hang tag as well. That tag was created by the Sunshine State Squires group on Facebook and available for purchase through them, though I don’t believe it is still available for purchase. There are a variety of dates of bottling for the 2020 edition of the Eric Church release, with some dates in June 2020 and July 2020. I have bottles with both 6/26/2020 and 7/23/2020 bottling dates. The Hunt The Eric Church Single Barrel release was a hard to find bottle in 2020, selling very quickly where available. On Wednesday July 29th I was able to track down a bottle in Texas which I ordered and had a family member pick up. That order is still sitting in my cousin’s house in Texas until we can find a time to meet up post covid. I found that Total Wine in Fairview Heights Illinois had it available online the morning of Saturday August 1st. I quickly placed an order for 3, packed the kids up in the car and headed out to run errands that morning. I was tempted to drive straight to IL to get them, but decided to stop and pick up a few fishing supplies before our camping trip that week. While shopping in Cabela’s I missed a call from Fairview Heights, I returned the call and was told that the bottles on the shelf were all sold in 1.5 hours, before they could pull my online order, so they were cancelling the order. Missed opportunity #1. On Wednesday August 12th a buddy of mine was able to locate availability via an online retailer in Florida. I placed an order of 2 bottles, one for me, one for him. Shortly after receiving that order the bottle also started showing up in the St. Louis market. In St. Louis I had a few interesting hunts. I was pretty much hitting the local shops almost daily, Total Wine and More in Chesterfield, Dogwood Liquors in Ellisville, The Wine and Cheese Place in Chesterfield, Randalls, without any luck. All the locations when asked about the Eric Church bottle said they had more questions about that bottle than anything else, and they had no idea when/how many they would get. One evening in a local bourbon group I saw rumors that Total Wine down in Town &amp;amp; Country had a bottle, so I headed off under the guise of buying school supplies for the kids and hit TW first. They had 5 bottles at the time, with a limit of purchasing 1 per person. I picked up a bottle and alerted a few friends who might be interested in picking one up. I then went to Wal-Mart with my son and purchased the needed school supplies, along with a $5 long sleeve T-Shirt for myself. After leaving Wal-Mart I changed my shirt, put on a different (covid) mask and went back to Total Wine and acquired a second bottle. I totally felt like a rebel. There were still 4 bottles visible on the shelf when I arrived, 3 when I left. A buddy of mine went at 9am the next morning and got a bottle from the same location. Later that next evening I went to Total Wine T&amp;amp;C again, the shelf row where the bottles were was empty, and the tag showed the dreaded green “out of stock” message that Total Wine uses. I was dejected, I had been hoping to grab a bottle for a friend. I decided I would dig a little bit, and guess what I found? One last bottle of Eric Church mixed in with the other Jack Daniel’s Single Barrel options. I grabbed it and checked out! I continued to check for more bottles at the TW in Chesterfield, each time apparently just missing when they had them available. From what I could gather, they had at least 3 cases available, one was out on Saturday August 23rd, another on Friday August 28th and early in the morning on Saturday August 29th. On Friday the 28th, I found another source online that showed the EC release was available in St. Louis. I placed an online order, trying to get three bottles from the location, and then “waited” for the order to be accepted. By the end of the work day, I was still waiting. I took off after work and went up to North County to the location that showed as having a bottle online, and was able to purchase one bottle at a price of $64 plus tax. The next day I received a cancellation of my online order, saying they were out of stock. Online however that location still shows availability. After the successful pickup, I stopped at a variety of other liquor stores on my way back over to west county and only found one more store that had any in stock. There is a liquor store on the Rock Road, I won’t name it, the girl behind the counter said they had some, but she wasn’t sure if she could sell it, it was under the counter behind the register. She called someone and asked them about the bottle, they told her she could sell it. She told me it was $250, I laughed as I walked out the door. I’ll keep hunting, a big part of the enjoyment in this whiskey game is that hunt. Where To Buy You can still find the bottle online, though not at many locations that will ship out of their home states. Bottle price as of August 2020 varies from $60 up to $250. Release: 2020 Proof: 94 Size: 750ml Price: $53.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tennessee Tasters’ Barrel Proof Rye</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TennesseeTastersBarrelProofRye" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tennessee Tasters’ Barrel Proof Rye" /><published>2020-08-30T17:32:40-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T17:32:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TennesseeTastersBarrelProofRye</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In July of 2019 Jack Daniel’s released the fourth bottle in their Tennessee Tasters’ series, Barrel Proof Rye, Straight Tennessee Rye Whiskey. The label reads: After tasting our Tennessee Rye Whiskey in its purst form - straight from the barrel - we longed to share it with our firneds. Maturing at the highest reached of barrel house #1-05 delivers a deep copper hue and a nose that opens with an aroma full of smoke and raisin, while each sip lingerswith moolasses, sawn oak, and bold rye spice. - Master Taster: Michael Myers As with all the Tasters’ Series these bottles were originally only available in Tennessee. You can still find it in select TN stores for $39.99. Release: 2019 Proof: 127.6 Size: 375ml Price: $39.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daytona Bike Week 2020 Collectors Bottle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/DaytonaBikeWeek2020" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daytona Bike Week 2020 Collectors Bottle" /><published>2020-04-15T23:26:58-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T23:26:58-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/DaytonaBikeWeek2020</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">Last fall I discovered that there are Facebook groups dedicated to Jack Daniel’s. I started following The Jack Cave, with Sue Scheel Clark. One a post there one day she mentioned the Sunshine State Squires and Collectors Facebook Group out of Florida, and that they were putting together some special edition bottles, and had previously done a few bottles as well. The first bottle that I learned about is one I hope to write about in the next week or two, as I don’t have it yet, but today I received my first bottle from the group.This bottle was put together for the 2020 Daytona Beach Bike Week. The bottle is a single barrel selection chosen by the group, and contains a number of very cool things! The first, most noticeable item is the custom sleeve, with a photoshopped picture combining Easy Rider and the ocean. It also contains a hang tag reading “Daytona Beach Bike Week 2020”.It contains a sticker, a coaster, and a custom coin, along with an etched bottle.The front of the coin reads the same as the logo on the sleeve:Daytona Beach, Florida79th Bike WeekWorld’s Largest Motorcycle Event2020The etched bottle reads the same as the coaster, and the back of the coin:Daytona Beach Bike WeekRide ResponsiblyBottles &amp;amp; Throttles Don’t Mix2020I ended up ordering two of these bottles, and 3 extra sleeves. As I’ve gotten into the various Facebook groups I’ve seen these custom bottles and sleeves that have “scenes”, and when you have multiple boxes next to each other you can see the full scene, you can see this in the photos below as I have a shot of one of the sleeves fully spread out.I look forward to partaking in future bottle sales that these groups do!Bottled: March 10, 2020Barrel Number: 20-01418Rick No.: L-17Release: March 2020Proof: 94Size: 750mlPrice: $75/bottle</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first whiskey tasting event</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/my-first-whiskey-tasting-event" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first whiskey tasting event" /><published>2020-02-12T23:01:49-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T23:01:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/my-first-whiskey-tasting-event</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been threatening for months that I was going to have a whiskey tasting event, this past Friday I finally did it. This post contains an overview of how I planned, how the event went and what lessons learned for future events.PlanningThe biggest hurdle to this event was just picking a date, for months I haven’t been able to get a date on the calendar, so in late January I threw one up (February 7th) and created a private Facebook event with info. I then sent the invite out to a small group of friends, some of which I had been talking about the event with for months. In the Facebook I included a list of various bottles that I had acquired for the purpose of drinking over the past year, including selections of Jack Daniel’s, and non Jack Daniel’s bottles. I also requested that everyone bring an unopened bottle of their own, an if they felt like leaving it afterward they could. I ended up extending the invites out to 11 people, 8 of whom were able to make it. As I neared the date I started prepping some things.I cleaned all my whiskey glasses, and wine glasses (not for use, but because they hadn’t been washed in…. years) I purchased some new tasting glasses, 8 of them, shaped like Glencairn glasses, but not the brand.I did a little reading on how best to host a whiskey tasting. (Google it) I posted a link to an article about “infinity” bottles, or the idea of filling up a decanter with a variety of different whiskeys, either when a bottle is opened, or as a bottle nears it’s completion. I suggested everyone bring a decanter and we could see about filling them up.I changed my mind about everyone bringing a decanter, and decided that I was going to buy some moonshine bottles and personalize them for the event (see the photos below, I think they turned out great).Made a selection of ice for the event, for anyone who wanted ice in their glasses (not everyone did).At 5pm that evening I headed to the local grocery store, hoping to score some snacks, and hoping to score some whiskey for the night. In the local Bourbon Facebook group there were substantiated rumors that you could find some Weller’s Reserve and Eagle Rare at the Dierberg’s around town, so I headed to the Wildwood location with hopes of finding one or both. I was able to fill up the cart with snacks, and a bottle of the Dierberg’s Single Barrel selection of the Eagle Rare.Final prep for the night of including getting the dining room table extended and bringing extra chairs up from the basement. I also picked up some crackers and pizza bites to warm up, in case anyone was hungry for something. The pizza bites didn’t last an hour.Event ExperienceCome the night of I was ready about an hour before the scheduled start time, so I sat down to read my copy of The Whiskey Advocate that mysteriously showed up in my mailbox a week ago. When the first guests showed up we took a seat in the kitchen and caught up a bit waiting for the rest of the crew to arrive.As everyone showed up, all bringing a bottle of their choice, I gave a tour of the basement where I keep my “undrinkables”, my Jack Daniel’s collection. From there we took our seats at the dining room table, the location for the tasting, and I passed out the custom decanters. Everyone got to choose a glass from the table, and then I tried to determine what we would start with. My original list on the invite had probably 12 different bottles of mine that I wanted to use, but I quickly realized that wasn’t going to be realistic, so we started with the guest provided bottles and mixed in 4 or 5 of mine throughout the night.Everyone got a “dram”, a small pour, supposed to be 3/4 of an OZ, but unmeasured on my pours. We went in the following order:Eagle Rare (90 Proof) Knob Creek Smoked Maple (90 proof)Tamdhu Scotch (96 Proof)New Riff Kentucky Straight Rye Bottled In Bond (100 proof)Breckenridge Bourbon Whiskey (86 proof)Sons of Erin Irish Whiskey (92 Proof)Woodford Reserve (90.4 Proof)Whistle Pig Farmstock Rye (86 Proof)Blanton’s (93 Proof)Jack Daniel’s Heritage Barrel 2019 (100 Proof)Jack Daniel’s No. 27 Gold (80 proof)George Dickel Bottled in Bond (100 proof)Outside of the tasting a few of us tried Bruichladdich The Classic Laddie, a scottish barley, which we mostly immediately regretted. We had quite the variety of things to choose from on our first tasting. In the future we’ll have to decide if we want to try that many in one go again or not. Overall consensus was that the Blanton’s was the best. After that it was mixed, but I think the Jack Daniel’s No. 27 Gold was extra smooth and drinkable. Definitely glad we cracked that one open.My buddy who brought the Whistle Pig Farmstock Rye brought me another bottle, we didn't open it, but I did get to keep it. It is a 100 Proof bottle of The Legendary Hatfield &amp; McCoy Family Brand Whiskey. I spent a few minutes looking online, and no proof of this bottle's existance can be found (you can find the 80 proof version, but I don't think 100 proof ever went to retail), how cool is that?Lessons LearnedOne, have fun. This was a great damn time. Invite some good friends, and invite some people you might not know that well. If you can get everyone to bring/leave a bottle, you can build up your collection! Be prepared, there was no way I had enough glasses for 9 people to try 12 different drinks. What we ended up doing was putting a bowl on each end of the table, and a pitcher of water. Rinsing the glasses out in between drams. This worked out pretty well, though I’m sure purists might cringe at the idea.Doing an infinite bottle/decanter might not make sense at a tasting like this, maybe that comes with some sort of a bring a bottle/trade pours type of thing.If I do this again in the future, no, not if, WHEN I do this again in the future, I will have to come up with another parting gift for everyone who attends.I am already trying to figure out when the next one is, likely in April 2020. Thinking I’ve got enough special edition Jack Daniel’s bottles we can crack open (in my drinkable selection) that we might just do a Night Dedicated To Jack Daniels.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Before and After Release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/before-after" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Before and After Release" /><published>2019-12-28T23:11:58-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T23:11:58-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/before-after</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">In the fall of 2019 rumors started swirling online of a new release available at the White Rabbit Bottleshop in Lynchburg, of a Before and After set. Two bottles of unmatured Old No. 7, one BEFORE Charcoal Mellowing and one AFTER Charcoal Mellowing, along with a small bottle of Hard Sugar Maple Charcoal in between the two bottles. The BEFORE bottle on the left, the AFTER on the right.It ends up the package was exclusive to Tennessee, and could be found at a variety of locations around the state. I lined up a set with a local in Lynchburg, and planned to get it in the mail, trading for a Scenes of Lynchburg series bottle, but got cold feet before shipping and ended up committing to the other party that I would trade in person next time I make it to Lynchburg.In November I made a trek south from St. Louis down to Memphis and picked up two packages of the Before and After set, maintaining my intention of getting the third set mentioned above.The bottles and charcoal come in a black box, the bottles with a white label with black text. The bottles are 375ml, with whiskey aged only one day.This set has a lot of writing on it, so I am not going to transcribe all of that writing this time around, but will include a couple of interesting bits.Tasting Directions1) Pour an ounce of our before charcoal mellowing whiskey into a tasking glass. Without mellowing, it’s nose has extra cereal notes and its taste is more harsh and oily in character.2) Pour an ounce of our after charcoal mellowing whiskey into a second glass. Because this whiskey has been mellowed drop by drop, you’ll notice its nose and taste is smoother and cleaner. It is absent the grainy character of the before mellowing Jack Daniel’s.One last thing, the bottle mentions a URL, jackdaniels.com/BEFORE-AFTER but as of December 28th, 2019, the URL only leads to a 404 page.Release: 2019Proof: 80Size: 375ml (x2)Price: $29.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 Jack Daniel’s Holiday Countdown Calendar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019AdventCalendar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 Jack Daniel’s Holiday Countdown Calendar" /><published>2019-12-19T10:41:16-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T10:41:16-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019AdventCalendar</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">For 2019 Jack Daniel’s has brought their holiday (advent) calendar across the pond to the United States! They’ve also made it available elsewhere around the globe this year as well, where I believe primarily over the past couple of years it was only available in the UK (I could be wrong on that fact).I spent quite a bit of time this fall trying to find this calendar in the St. Louis market, but no stores that I talked to knew anything about it, and from what I can tell no one in the St. Louis market got any in for sale. I ended up driving to Memphis a few weeks back and picked up 3 for myself. 1 to open (see my instagram feed for the daily opening), 1 to keep, and 1 to have as a tradeable item in the future.The countdown calendar comes with 20 50ML bottles, and 4 shot glasses. The bottles are a mix of Tennessee Honey, Old #7, Tennessee Fire, Gentleman Jack, Single Barrel Select and Rye.The front of the box readsJack Daniel Distillery Lynchburg Tenn.Holiday Countdown CalendarThe back has the logos, and a description of each of the various libations along with Happy Holidays from Our Family to YoursIn Lynchburg, Tennessee, the holidays are about traditions old and new. While old traditions warm the heart, there’s something special about starting a new one. We hope that as you open a new calendar door, you’ll share a toast with the folks closest to you.Each day, the 1st through the 24th, has a separate door that you open to find the present for the day. In the first week or so you'll find three shot glasses, the fourth one comes later in the month. The doors can be a little difficult to open without causing bending of the cardboard, but if you're careful it can be done. \tIf you can get your hands on one of these countdown calendars, enjoy! Overseas they can be found in a variety of locations at a discount as the month is half over, here in the US though they appear to still be hard to find.Happy Holidays!Release: 2019Proof: VariesSize: 20 x 50mlPrice: $89.99</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Apple</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TennesseeApple" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Apple" /><published>2019-11-26T09:12:18-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-26T09:12:18-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TennesseeApple</id><author><name>Chris Hammond</name></author><summary type="html">With the release of Jack Honey and Fire over the past 10 years, it was time for Jack Daniel’s to catch the apple train and release their own Tennessee Apple Liqueur. I was able to get some here in Missouri earlier this fall from lukasliquorstl.com.The 750ml bottle comes in the usual Jack Daniel’s shape with a green gold and white label. The front of the bottle reads:Jack Daniel’s Original RecipeTennessee AppleFinely CraftedApple Liqueur Blended with Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey35% ALC. By Vol. (70 Proof)One side of the bottle reads:Smooth FlavorTennessee Apple has the distinct character of Jack Daniel’s Tennessee Whiskey coupled with crisp green apple for a fresh &amp;amp; rewarding taste.Enjoy ChilledCaramel Colored The other side reads:Jack Daniel’s CharacterLynchburg, TennClassic Green AppleCrisp &amp;amp; FreshExceptionally SmoothHighest QualityThe back reads:Distilled &amp;amp; Bottled by Jack Daniel Distillery Lynchburg, Tenn USAThe bottle can be found at retailers everywhere, and as I understand it, is around for a while, so it shouldn’t be too hard to track down.Release: 2019Proof: 70Size: 750mlPrice: $22.99</summary></entry></feed>